舰长，我觉得自己开始喜欢埃及列斯了
Captain, I think I'm going to like Argelius.
很有品味嘛
Obviously a man of good taste.
你是想说，所有这些女人，所有这些…？
You mean to tell me that all these women, that all this is..?
没错没错
Yes, yes, yes.
埃及列斯人很会享受
The Argelians think very highly of their pleasure.
我曾经听过这种说法
That's an understatement if I ever heard one.
他们的社会信奉快乐至上
This is a completely hedonistic society.
- 你喜欢她吗，史考特 - 喜欢
- Do you like her, Scotty? - Aye.
- 怎么会不喜欢呢？ - 很好
- Why shouldn't I? - Good.
我邀请了她和我们同桌，你会喜欢她的
I've invited her to join us at the table. I thought you might like to meet her.
这才是好舰长嘛，总是替自己的手下着想
Now, that's what I call a real captain. Always thinking of his men.
史考特，史考特，埃及列斯人用灯光表示喝彩
Scotty, Scotty, on Argelius they use the lights.
我可是苏格兰人，酒馆礼仪还是懂的
No one has to tell an old Aberdeen pub crawler how to applaud, captain.
请坐吧
Have one of our pillows?
今晚薄雾弥漫，格外美丽 有没有跟你讲过
'Tis a fine foggy night tonight, and I doubt if anyone has ever told you
我们亚伯丁的绝美雾色
of the marvellous fogs we have in Aberdeen.
从没有
Never a word.
- 但是我很想知道 - 那我就带你去看看吧？
- But I'm dying to learn. - Well, then, why don't I show you?
没什么比和美丽姑娘在薄雾中散步更令人向往了
There's nothing like a walk in the fog with a bonny lass.
或是和英俊的先生
Or a handsome gentleman.
请吧？
Why don't we?
你不介意吧？我会按时回舰的
You don't mind, do you? I might even get back to the ship on time.
我们不会丢下你的，史考特，玩的开心点
We won't leave without you, Scotty. Relax and enjoy yourself.
我的工作永远做不完
My work is never done.
我的工作，就是开处方
My work, Jim. This is prescription stuff.
别忘了，那次爆炸史考特被甩到隔板上
Don't forget, the explosion that threw Scotty against the bulkhead
就是为一个女人
was caused by a woman.
但是他身体没事，对吧？
Physically, he's all right. Am I right in assuming that?
没错，不过呢
Oh, yes, yes. Matter of fact,
可能会造成不小的心理伤害啊
considerable psychological damage could have been caused.
比如说，他对女性的怨恨
For example, his total resentment toward women.
目前看来他可一点都不怨恨女人啊
He seems to be overcoming his resentment.
以我的专业意见，等他回舰
In my professional opinion, when he gets back to the ship
就会怨你逼他离开埃及列斯了
he's going to hate you for making him leave Argelius.
但是那时候，他就完全不会怨恨女人了
But then, he will have lost total resentment toward women.
史考特的任务已经完成了
Mission accomplished, as far as Scotty is concerned.
老骨头，我知道镇上有个地方，那里的女人…
Bones, I know a little place across town where the women...
哦，我知道那地方，我知道
Oh, yes, I know the place. I know the place. Let's go.
- 是这边吧 - 是这边
- I think it's that way. - I think it's that way too.
- 她死了，吉姆 - 被刺了十几刀
- She's dead, Jim. - Stabbed a dozen times.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十四集
「狼入羊圈」
舰长日志，星历3614.9，埃及列斯II行星
Captain's log, stardate 3614.9. Planet Argelius II.
靠岸疗养期间，史考特先生涉嫌
While on therapeutic shore leave, Mr. Scott has fallen under suspicion
残忍杀害一名埃及列斯女性
of having brutally murdered an Argelian woman.
当地行政长官，亨吉斯
The chief city administrator, a Mr. Hengist,
负责整个事件调查，但目前案情并不明朗
has taken charge of the investigation, but has learned little of value.
我不知道说什么，各位
I don't know what to say, gentlemen.
我万万没有想到埃及列斯会发生这种事情
Argelius is the last planet in the galaxy I'd expect a thing like this to happen.
我们也非常震惊，亨吉斯先生
We're just as shocked as you are, Mr. Hengist.
如果这是在我的家乡参宿七-4行星 我能找到足够的调查员
If this was my home planet, Rigel IV, I'd have a dozen investigators
参与调查，但是这里没有
working on the matter. But they don't exist here.
您不是埃及列斯人？
You're not a native of Argelius, sir?
不是，埃及列斯人会从其他行星雇佣行政官员
No. Argelius hires its administrative officers from other planets.
埃及列斯人在这方面效率不高 他们都是无辜淳朴的人
The Argelians aren't very efficient, you know. Gentle, harmless people.
史考特先生，史考特先生？
Mr. Scott. Mr. Scott?
你确定以前从来没见过这个？
Now, are you sure you've never seen this before?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
真的？先生，这样可没什么用
Really, sir. That is hardly helpful.
史考特，你跟一个姑娘一起离开了咖啡馆，记得吗？
Scotty, you left the café with the girl. Do you remember that?
后来发生了什么？
What happened next?
我们在雾中…
We were walking...
走着…
...the fog...
…我走在前面，带路
...I was up ahead, trying to lead the way.
听到她尖叫
I heard the girl scream.
我记得准备转身
I remember starting to turn.
- 然后就不记得了 - 史考特，你得努力回忆才行
- I don't remember another thing. - Scotty, you've got to remember.
吉姆
Jim.
他说自己不记得了估计就是不记得了 你了解史考特的
If he says he can't remember, he probably doesn't. You know Scotty.
我了解的是，发生了一桩谋杀案
I know that a murder has been committed.
我不会认为是史考特…
You don't think by any chance Scotty...
我怎么认为不重要
It doesn't make any difference what I think.
你不能就这么把他扔进虎口啊
You don't just throw him to the wolves.
老骨头，我身负外交责任
Bones, I have a diplomatic responsibility.
这件事发生在埃及列斯司法管辖区
This happened under Argelian jurisdiction.
如果他们要逮捕他，审判他，给他定罪
If they want to arrest him, try him, even convict him,
我也只能听之任之
I have to go along with it.
但是他现在受到了严重惊吓
But he's suffering from a severe concussion.
我们会尽力而为的
We'll do what we can.
舰长，情况并不乐观，史考特先生还是什么都想不起来
It's not promising, captain. Mr. Scott insists he remembers nothing.
但是检测器检测结果显示 凶器上只有他的指纹
But my detector readings indicate only his fingerprints on the murder weapon.
亨吉斯先生，谋杀发生时咖啡馆还有其他人
Mr. Hengist, there were other people in the café at the time of the murder.
史考特先生和那女孩离开之前还有其他人离开
Several of them left just before Mr. Scott and the girl did.
咖啡馆员工跟我们说了这个情况
So I've been informed by the staff.
已经找到这些人了，我们会询问他们的
They're being located, and we will question them.
但是你朋友的前景很不乐观
But the outlook for your friend is quite grim.
法律关于这类案件是怎么规定的？
What is the law in these cases?
爱就是埃及列斯的普世律法
The law of Argelius is love.
各位，这是我们的行政长官，嘉利斯
Gentlemen, our prefect, Jaris.
先生，这是寇克舰长和麦考伊医生
Sir, Captain Kirk and Dr. McCoy.
这位是我妻子，赛柏
And this is my wife, Sybo.
这个就是史考特，我在讯息里跟你说过的
And this man is Scott, the one I sent you the message about.
他看起来不像会做出这种事的人
He does not look like a man capable of such an act.
不过，已经过了这么久
Still, it's been so long.
各位，200年前我们迎来了大觉醒，在那之前
Gentlemen, before our great awakening 200 years ago
碰到这种事情，我们自有一套寻找真相的办法
we had ways of learning the truth in such matters.
我们应寻求古老传统的帮助
We shall return to them.
- 埃及列斯移情法？ - 你听说过？
- The Argelian empathic contact? - You know of this?
听说过，不过我以为这种艺术已经失传了
Yes, we've heard of it. I assumed it was a lost art.
我的妻子是上古女祭司的后人
My wife is a descendant of the ancient priestesses of our land.
她继承了这一传统
She has the ancestral gift.
我是来请各位光临寒舍的
Gentlemen, I have come to invite you to my home.
长官，您不觉得这件事还是在
Prefect, don't you think this should be handled
我的办公室，通过官方渠道解决比较好？
in an official manner through my office?
是应该通过官方渠道解决，亨吉斯先生
It shall be handled in an official manner, Mr. Hengist,
而我就是最高行政长官
since I am the highest official.
先生们，请各位前往寒舍，借助我妻子的帮助
Gentlemen, let's proceed to my home, where, with the aid of my wife,
我们便能看到真相
we shall learn the truth.
请
Please.
依靠您妻子的移情能力来寻找真相当然很好
Depending on your wife's empathic abilities is all very well, prefect,
但是还有一个办法可以让我们搞清楚 史考特先生忘记的事情
but there's one way we can find out what it is Mr. Scott cannot remember.
鉴于你们觉得让我们返回星舰是不可能的
Since you find it impossible to let us go back up to our ship,
我可以传送一小队技术人员下来
I can beam down a technician with a psychotricorder.
长官，这样我们就可以搞清楚
Prefect, it will give us a detailed account
过去24小时，史考特先生到底怎么了
of everything that's happened to Mr. Scott in the last 24 hours.
我反对，长官，这是埃及列斯人的事情
I'd advise against it, prefect. This is purely an Argelian matter.
我妻子需要冥想一段时间才能准备好
My wife must meditate for a time before she is ready.
为何不好好利用这段时间呢
I see no reason why we should not use that time to good advantage.
- 好吧，舰长 - 寇克呼叫进取号
- Very well, captain. - Kirk to Enterprise.
收到，我是史波克
Enterprise, Spock here.
史波克先生，请传送一小队技术人员下来
Mr. Spock, beam down a technician with a psychotricorder, please.
坐标已发送
Use these coordinates.
- 收到坐标 - 完毕
- Acknowledged. Coordinates received. - Kirk out.
长官，技术人员需要一些空间
Prefect, the psychotricorder will require privacy
以便提高效率
in order to be effective.
这个房间下面有个小室
There is a small chamber below this room.
应该可以了吧
Perhaps that will suffice.
舰长…
Captain...
…关于谋杀的消息…
...news of this frightful murder...
已经传到了我的人民耳中，他们很不安
...is spreading among my people. They're greatly disturbed.
我已经听到了有传言说要把 埃及列斯人关进宇宙飞船里
I have already heard talk of closing Argelius to space vehicles.
这真是太糟糕了
Well, that would be most unfortunate.
埃及列斯人的好客是远近闻名的
Argelian hospitality is well-known,
而且也是具有重大战略意义的航天港
as well as its strategic importance as a space port.
没错，它是这一区域唯一的航天港
Yes, I believe it's the only one in the quadrant.
舰长
Captain.
还有其他人需要询问
There are other people we should question.
我去通知他们前来吧
Perhaps I should go expedite their arrival here?
有劳了，亨吉斯先生
Please do so, Mr. Hengist.
任何与谋杀有关联的人都应出现在仪式上
Anyone connected with this murder should be present at the ceremony.
上尉凯伦·特雷西向您报道，舰长
Lieutenant Karen Tracy reporting as ordered, captain.
上尉，我需要史考特过去24小时的全部回忆
Lieutenant, I want a 24-hour regressive memory check made on Mr. Scott.
是，舰长，要在哪里进行呢？
Yes, captain. Where shall I set up?
请随我来，上尉
If you will just follow me, lieutenant.
史考特，你要配合特雷西上尉
Scotty, cooperate completely with Lieutenant Tracy.
- 希望能澄清这件事 - 我也希望如此
- Maybe we can clear this thing up. - I certainly hope so, sir.
我不能忍受自己回忆不起来
I can't stand this not knowing.
舰长，正常情况下
Captain, under normal conditions,
史考特绝不会做出这种事的
Scotty would have never done such a thing.
但是他头上那一击
But that blow on the head.
会让他完全忘了之前的行为
It could put all his previous behaviour patterns into the junk heap.
- 当然，还有别的可能性 - 说说
- Of course, there is another possibility. - Explain.
癔症性遗忘
Hysterical amnesia.
当一个人对某件可怕的事情感到愧疚不愿回忆起时
When a man feels guilty about something too terrible to remember
会下意识的选择性遗忘
he blots it out of his conscious memory.
- 你准备好了吗，赛柏？ - 准备好了
- Are you ready, Sybo? - I am ready.
- 请把刀给我 - 好的
- May I have the knife, please? - Certainly.
除了其他赠礼之外，赛柏还有从无生命物体中
Among other gifts, Sybo has the ability to receive impressions
获取想法的能力
from inanimate objects.
在你那里吗，舰长？
Do you have it, captain?
刀？没有啊
The knife? No.
我们进来时我放在这里的，不见了
But I put it here when we arrived. It's gone.
史考特
Scotty.
她死了，吉姆
She's dead, Jim.
就像之前一样
Just like the other one.
被捅了很多刀
Stabbed over and over again.
喝了这个
Drink this.
一种埃及列斯兴奋剂，医生 很有效，而且无害
An Argelian stimulant, doctor. Quite effective and quite harmless.
喝吧，史考特
Go ahead, Scotty.
上尉…
Lieutenant...
舰长，那个…？
Captain. Where's..?
特雷西上尉死了，史考特，房间里只有你一个人
Lieutenant Tracy is dead, Scott. You were found alone in the room.
- 死了？但是… - 发生什么事了？
- Dead? But... - What happened down there?
我…
I was...
…坐在那里
...sitting there.
她开始拿设备检测…
She was taking the readings...
…现在我又坐在这里
...and now I'm sitting here.
就这么多？
Is that all that happened?
我告诉你了，我想不起来了 我一定是昏过去了
I tell you, I don't remember. I must have passed out.
有可能，吉姆，他头上受过伤
It could be, Jim. That head injury.
是啊
Yeah.
头上受过伤
That head injury.
想想，史考特
Think, Scotty.
舰长，我在想
Captain, I've been trying.
不敢相信真的发生了这么可怕的事情
I can't even believe this is really happening.
从这里没法进到那里
There's no way into that place from up here.
长官
Prefect.
还有别的入口可以进入地下小室吗？
Is there another entrance to that chamber?
有一扇门是通向花园的
Yes, there's a door that leads into the garden.
但是那扇门已经被锁上很多年了
But that's been locked for years.
- 锁是可以撬开的，吉姆 - 查查看
- Locks can be picked, Jim. - Check it.
长官，谋杀发生当晚这些人都在咖啡馆
Prefect, both of these men were at the café the night of the murder.
他们刚才在哪里？
Where have they been the past few minutes?
- 舰长，如果你不介意的话… - 又发生了一起谋杀案
- Captain, if you don't mind, please... - There's been another murder.
- 我的一个船员 - 和卡拉一样
- One of my crew. - The same as Kara.
怎么会这样，太可怕了
Why, that's terrible.
嘿，我的人在这附近见到了你，你当时在做什么？
You. My men picked you up near here. What were you doing?
我什么都不知道，我没有杀人
Please. I know nothing about it. I didn't kill anyone.
- 那姑娘是怎么死的？ - 被刀刺死的
- How was the girl killed? - Stabbed.
没有凶器的痕迹
And there's no sign of the weapon.
- 要是有设备… - 你
- If only I had facility... - You.
你是咖啡馆的演奏师，当时为那被杀的女孩伴奏
You were a musician at the café. You played for the murdered girl.
她还是个小女孩的时候，就开始为我跳舞
Since she was a little girl, she danced for me.
她是我的女儿
She was my daughter.
长官，怎么会发生这种事
Prefect, how could a thing like this have happened here?
一定要找到凶手，一定要让他接受惩罚
The man who did it must be found. He must be punished.
还有你
And you.
你在斯考特和卡拉之前离开了咖啡馆
You left the café before Scott and Kara.
这是真的吗？你是谁？
Is this true? Who are you?
坎特巴大街的莫拉，长官，我是在那里，没什么好隐瞒的
Morla of Cantaba Street, prefect. I was there. I have nothing to hide.
你认识卡拉？
Did you know Kara?
当然认识，他俩是夫妻
Of course he knew her. They were to be married.
但是他行为不端，前所未有
But he behaved disgraceful, unheard of.
他嫉妒她
He was jealous of her.
- 真是让人担心 - 我知道那样不对，长官
- That is very disquieting. - I know it was wrong, prefect,
但我情不自禁，我爱她…
but I just couldn't help myself. I loved her...
…看见她走过去，跟那些男人在一起
...and when she went over to the table with these men,
感觉自己看不下去，所以我离开咖啡馆回家了
I just could not stand to watch, so I left. I went home.
很多时候嫉妒是谋杀的动机
Jealousy has often been a motive for murder.
对，我知道
Yes, I know.
所以这里的气氛才如此紧张
That is why the emotion is so strongly disapproved of here.
长官，我没有杀人，这不可能啊
Prefect, I didn't kill anyone. I couldn't.
我们会搞清楚的，莫拉
We shall see, Morla.
抱歉，吉姆，没法弄清楚锁有没有被撬过
Sorry, Jim. The lock may or may not have been picked.
就算有三录仪也很难说清
Be hard to tell, even with the tricorder.
你能证明自己是直接回家了吗？
Can you prove you went directly home?
舰长，我可以继续提问吗？
Captain, may I continue with the questions, please?
赶紧继续啊，别傻站在那儿
Well, get on with it, man, just don't stand there.
舰长，你现在的表现
Captain, you are behaving very much like a man
仿佛不惜一切要拯救自己朋友
who is desperately trying anything to save his friend.
你在挽留埃及列斯作为舰队港口的时候
Would you be as desperate to save Argelius
也会这么气急败坏吗？
as a space port for your Starfleet?
我当然要想办法救自己的朋友…
Well, of course I'm trying to save my friend...
…如果他是无辜的话，而他现在还没被定罪
...if he's innocent. And he hasn't been proven guilty.
要我提醒一下你现在的情况吗，舰长？
Need I remind you of the circumstances, captain?
不管凶手是谁，你的朋友斯考特都在尸体旁被发现
In both cases, your friend Scott was discovered over the body,
然后又称自己什么都不记得
and later claimed to remember nothing.
我准备好了，嘉利斯
I am ready, Jaris.
各位，请坐吧
Gentlemen, sit down, please.
长官，我有一个条件：
On one condition, prefect:
房门应紧闭，这样在仪式进行的时候
That the room be sealed so that no one can leave or enter
可以确保无人进出
while the ceremony is going on.
已经紧闭了
The room is sealed.
舰长，你要把我的性命交给这个
Captain, do you mean my neck is going to depend
装神弄鬼的疯女人？
on some spooky mumbo-jumbo?
- 我是寇克 - 我是史波克，舰长
- Kirk here. - Spock here, captain.
- 能跟你说几句话吗？ - 好
- May I have a word with you? - Yes.
失陪一下，各位
Excuse me, gentlemen.
说吧，史波克先生
Yes, Mr. Spock.
考虑到我们现在所处的情况
Concerning the situation you related to us,
我认为，埃及列斯移情法
in my opinion, the Argelian empathic contact
是一种很有趣的现象
is an interesting phenomenon.
但是这种技术还不成熟，不值得拿一个人的生命去冒险
But the technique is not sound enough to risk a man's life.
那你的意见呢，史波克先生？
What do you suggest, Mr. Spock?
很简单，我们将史考特先生传回进取号
Simply that we beam Mr. Scott onboard the Enterprise
然后用计算机来寻找真相
and employ our computers to learn the truth.
他们都是很骄傲的人，有自己的传统，自己的律法
These are a proud people. They have their own customs, their own laws.
既然我们在这里，就要入乡随俗
And while we're here, we're subject to them.
我们必须这么做
It is absolutely imperative
这件事必须按照埃及列斯律法来解决，明白了吗？
that this matter be resolved according to Argelian law. Is that clear?
是，舰长
Quite clear, captain.
我也很不愿意这样，但是我们必须这么做
I don't like it any more than you do, but there's nothing we can do about it.
完毕
Kirk out.
开始吧，不要打破圆圈
Let us begin. Let the circle not be broken.
仔细看那火焰，它在真理的圣坛上燃烧
Concentrate upon the flame which burns upon the Altar of Truth.
是啊
Yes.
我看到了一些事情
There is something here.
可怕的事情，我能感受到它的存在
Something terrible. I feel its presence.
恐惧、愤怒、憎恨
Fear, anger, hatred.
愤怒喂养着火焰
Anger feeds the flame.
我看到了恶魔，鬼怪，可怕的恶魔
There is evil here, monstrous, terrible evil.
饥饿的吞噬者
Consuming hunger.
憎恨所有生灵，憎恨女人
Hatred of all that lives, hatred of women.
永生不死的饥饿
A hunger that never dies.
强大无比，势不可挡
It is strong, overpowering.
古老的恶魔，它的名字是
An ancient terror. It has a name.
博拉迪斯，科斯拉，瑞吉克
Beratis, Kesla, Redjac.
吞噬所有生命，所有光明
Devouring all life, all light.
永生不死的饥饿
A hunger that will never die!
瑞吉克！瑞吉克！
Redjac! Redjac!
三起谋杀案
Three murders,
每一次凶手都指向斯考特
and Scotty the only possible answer each time.
我不管情况是什么，吉姆
I don't care what the circumstances indicate, Jim.
- 斯考特不可能杀人的 - 正常情况下是不会
- Scotty simply could not have done it. - Normally, no.
- 可是他头上的伤… - 不，舰长…
- But that blow on his head could... - No, captain.
斯考特，对不起
Scotty, I'm sorry.
你甚至都想不起来自己究竟有没有做过
You don't even remember whether you did it or not.
我同意你，舰长
I agree with you, captain.
我很满意，斯考特先生的确有罪
I am perfectly satisfied Mr. Scott is guilty.
- 但不是他的责任 - 这点还没法证明
- But not responsible. - That is unproven.
- 我们可以证明他是否失去了理智 - 各位
- We can prove it. If he's insane. - Gentlemen, please.
怎么会有人做出如此可怕的事情？
How could any man do such monstrous things?
我们也想搞清楚，先生
That's what we hope to find out, sir.
斯考特先生？
Mr. Scott?
我发誓，我没有谋杀你妻子
Sir, I swear to you, I did not kill your wife
也没有谋杀其他女人
or the other ladies.
你自己也承认了，不清楚自己是不是杀了人
By your own admission, you don't know whether you did or didn't.
- 你自称“失忆”… - 亨吉斯先生
- Your so-called failing memory... - Mr. Hengist.
如果在进取号上，我们可以对斯考特先生的
On the Enterprise we can make a recording of the registrations
下意识和潜意识活动进行记录
of Mr. Scott's conscious and subconscious mind.
这样就可以搞清楚之前他到底做了什么
And they will tell us what happened to him in the recent past.
不要再猜疑了，我们会搞清楚
There would be no room for doubt. We would know.
毕竟我们要寻找的是真相，没错吧，长官？
And after all, that's what we're after, isn't it, prefect? To know?
先生，你声称不记得关于谋杀的任何细节
You, sir, claim to remember nothing about the murders.
是
Aye.
如果是这样，有可能你是在不知情的情况下杀了人
If this is so, you may have killed without knowing it.
你的仪器也会如实说明吗？
Will your machines tell us this?
当然
No doubt will remain.
很好
Very well.
我们就去你的星舰吧
We will go to your ship.
有罪的人会面临最古老的惩罚
And he who is guilty will face the ancient penalties,
甚至会有些野蛮和恐怖
barbaric and horrible though they may be.
对于谋杀罪的古老惩罚，便是折磨致死
The ancient penalty for murder was death by slow torture.
此条律法从未改变
That law has never been changed.
你明白了吗，斯考特先生？
Do you understand that, Mr. Scott?
我明白
Aye, I understand.
舰长日志，星历3615.4
Captain's log, stardate 3615.4.
鉴于斯考特先生目前实际处于监禁状态
With Mr. Scott in a technical state of arrest,
我们回到了进取号继续进行调查
we've beamed aboard the Enterprise to continue the investigation.
每名证人都要坐在这里，将手放在此平面
Each testifier will sit here, place his hand on this plate.
若证人口述与事实不否，仪器会立即检测到
Any deviation from the factual truth will be immediately detected
并传到这台计算机上，我们就可以看到了
and relayed to this computer, which will, in turn, notify us.
麦考伊医生已经把他的医疗记录输入计算机了
Dr. McCoy has already fed the computer his medical reports.
我们实验室的专家也正在检查凶器
Our laboratory experts are examining the murder weapon
会把分析结果输入计算机中
and will give their data to the computers for analysis.
我们开始吧？
Shall we begin?
斯考特先生，请就位吧
Mr. Scott, will you take the stand?
计算机，确认身份
Computer, identity verification.
处理中，蒙哥马利·斯考特少校
Working. Lieutenant Commander Montgomery Scott.
编号：SE-19754-T
Serial number: SE 19754T.
已确认
Verified.
目前当前身体状况？
Subject's present physical condition?
处理中，目标近期颅骨受到过袭击
Working. Subject recently received severe blow on skull.
损伤愈合中，神经末梢有异常
Damage healing. Some peripheral abnormalities.
此异常是否能够造成功能性记忆缺失？
Sufficient abnormalities to account for periods of functional amnesia?
处理中，否
Working. Negative.
舰长，我不明白怎么会这样
Captain, I don't see how that can be.
除非斯考特在记忆缺失这件事上撒谎
Unless Scotty's lying about his loss of memory.
我没撒谎，舰长
I'm not lying, captain.
关于前两起谋杀我什么都不记得了
I don't remember a thing about the first two murders.
计算机，精确性检测
Computer, accuracy scan.
目标陈述准确性分析 无生理变化
Subject relaying accurate account. No physiological changes.
舰长…
Captain...
…嘉利斯先生的妻子被杀害时我没有晕过去
...I didn't black out when Mr. Jaris' wife was killed.
好了，斯考特，说来听听
All right, Scotty. Let's have it.
我们当时拉着手
We were holding hands.
灯灭的时候，圆圈被打破了
When the lights went out, the circle was broken.
我听见可怜的夫人尖叫
I heard the poor lady scream
就朝长桌那头走去
and, as I was near the head of the table anyway,
快到她身边时，感觉到有什么东西挡路
I went toward her, but there was something in my way.
什么东西？你是说，有人
Something? You mean, someone.
不是，舰长，是什么东西
No, captain. Something.
非常寒冷，仿佛从屠杀场飘来的肮脏寒流
Cold it was, like a stinking draught out of a slaughterhouse.
但是又像是不在那里
But it wasn't really there.
像是…
Like...
你明白吗
If you know what I mean.
计算机？
Computer?
目标陈述准确性分析 无生理变化
Subject relaying accurate account. No physiological changes.
好了，说重点吧
All right. Let's hit it on the head.
斯考特，是不是你杀了赛柏？
Scotty, did you kill Sybo?
不是，舰长，我很确定
No, captain. That I'm sure of.
他一直这么说，并没有什么意义
He's been saying that right along. Means no more now than it did before.
斯考特，对我撒谎，你多大了？
Scotty, lie to me. How old are you?
22岁，舰长
Twenty-two, sir.
错误，错误，数据错误
Inaccurate, inaccurate. Data in error.
灯熄灭以后，你拉着谁的手？
After the lights went out, Mr. Scott, who was holding your hand?
一边是莫拉，一边是你
Morla on the one side, and you on the other, sir.
这说明不了什么，舰长
But that doesn't mean anything, captain,
房间那么小，灯又灭掉了
with a room that small. The lights were out.
谁都可以有时间杀了夫人的
Anyone would have had time to kill the lady.
但是容我提醒一句，我们发现的时候 她倒在斯考特先生怀里…
But I remind you, we found Mr. Scott holding her in his arms. The knife...
抱歉，但我必须得说
I'm sorry, sir, but I must.
而她背上有刀，他手上则有血
The knife still in her back, and blood on his hands.
他说自己没有杀她的时候
The verifier showed that he was telling the truth
仪器显示没有撒谎
when he said he didn't kill her.
还有两名女子也被谋杀了
There were two other women murdered.
斯考特先生…
Mr. Scott...
…是你杀了卡拉吗？ - 我不记得了
...did you kill Kara? - I don't remember.
- 是你杀了特雷西上尉吗？ - 我不记得了
- Did you kill Lieutenant Tracy? - I don't remember.
计算机，分析准确性
Computer, accuracy scan.
目标陈述准确性分析 无生理变化
Subject relaying accurate account. No physiological changes.
这只能证明他说自己什么
All that proves is that he's telling the truth
- 都不记得的时候，没有撒谎 - 这简直是浪费时间
- when he says he doesn't remember. - This is a waste of time.
等采集完证词，我们会用心理三录仪
After we take the testimony here, we'll run a psychotricorder analysis
对斯考特先生的记忆进行分析，这是表层的
of Mr. Scott's memory, which is what we wanted to do on the surface.
然后便可以拿到完整记录了 这样您满意吗，亨吉斯先生？
That will give us a complete record. Will that satisfy you, Mr. Hengist?
这…
Well...
如果你能说服我这仪器不会出错
If you can convince me that the machine is incapable of error
并能说明他没有杀人
and if it shows he didn't kill the women.
仪器不会出错
There will be no error.
其他的自会见分晓
As for the rest of it, the readings will show.
你可以下来了，斯考特先生，如果没人反对的话
I think you can step down now, Mr. Scott, if there are no objections.
我反对这整个程序
I object to the entire procedure.
亨吉斯先生，我们来到此是经过授权的
Mr. Hengist, we are here on my authority.
既来之则安之
We will cooperate.
长官，我知道你是出于好意，但是我有经验…
Prefect, I know you mean well, but I've had experience...
现在，我们先听听寇克舰长关于
For the time being, we will accept Captain Kirk's explanation
这台仪器事实准确性的解释
of the machine's accuracy as factual.
但是，我也保留自己做出最后决定的权利
I do, however, reserve to myself the right to make the final determination.
这样我们就别无所求了 莫拉先生，请你就位好吗？
We can ask no more. Mr. Morla, will you take the stand?
卡拉被谋杀的时候你在哪里？
Where were you at the time that Kara was murdered?
我不确定，应该是在回家的路上
I'm not sure. Walking home, I assume.
我当时很生气
I was angry.
生气是一个相对的状态，先生
Anger is a relative state, sir.
你是否生气到了会做出暴力举动的地步？
Were you angry enough to do violence?
我一辈子从来没有什么暴力举动 我不可能那样的
I've never done violence in my life. I don't think that I could.
你们一定要相信我 我没有杀她
You've got to believe me. I wouldn't kill her. I couldn't.
我爱她，她也爱我
I loved her, and she loved me.
你说谎
That's not true.
他以为她爱他，实则不然
He might think she loved him, but she didn't.
她告诉过我，他当时嫉妒了…
She told me. He was jealous...
…一直都是，他们经常争吵
...all the time. They fought constantly.
- 是你杀了特雷西上尉吗？ - 不是
- Did you kill Lieutenant Tracy? - No.
- 是你杀了赛柏吗？ - 不是
- Did you kill Sybo? - No.
计算机，分析准确性
Computer, verification scan.
目标陈述准确，部分陈述较主观
Subject relaying accurate account, though some statements subjective.
无生理变化
No physiological changes.
好了，莫拉先生，你可以下来了
All right, Mr. Morla. I think you can step down now.
赛柏死前提到了某种永生不死的饥饿
Sybo spoke of a hunger that never dies.
某种依赖害怕、恐惧和死亡
Something that thrives on fear,
生长的东西
terror, death.
史波克先生，可能我们调查的方向错了
Mr. Spock, maybe we're going about it the wrong way.
我们假设赛柏确有通灵能力
Let's assume that Sybo was a sensitive,
而且她的确感知到某种邪恶的东西
that she did sense something, something evil.
根据记录，有些埃及列斯女性确实有通灵能力，舰长
The sensitivity of certain Argelian women is a documented fact, captain.
我可怜的赛柏的确是有此项天赋的，各位
My poor Sybo's talent was genuine, gentlemen.
- 她说的是事实 - 那好
- What she told you was true. - All right, then.
她当时究竟是怎么说的？ 可怕的邪灵，古老的恶魔…
What was it she said, exactly? Monstrous evil, ancient terror...
吞噬一切生命与光明
That devours all life and light.
她还提到了别的，听不懂是什么意思的词
She said something else, words that didn't make any sense.
是，瑞吉克、博拉迪斯…
Yes. Redjac, Beratis...
…还有科斯拉
...and Kesla.
- 都是些晦涩、无意义的词 - 对我们无意义而已
- Obscure, meaningless words. - To us, perhaps,
- 但是对计算机来说… - 史波克先生，查查看
- but to the computer... - Mr. Spock, check them out.
计算机，语言资料库，以下单词的定义：
Computer, linguistic bank. Definition of following word:
瑞吉克
Redjac.
处理中，无结果
Working. Negative finding.
语言资料库中没有结果？
There is no such word in the linguistics bank?
是
Affirmative.
- 扫描全部资料库 - 处理中
- Scan all other banks. - Working. Affirmative.
- 专有名称 - 定义
- A proper name. - Define.
瑞吉克，来源：地球，19世纪
Redjac. Source: Earth, 19th century.
语言：英语
Language: English.
多起女性谋杀案凶手的绰号
Nickname for mass murderer of women.
其他地球同义词：开膛手杰克
Other Earth synonym: Jack the Ripper.
开膛手杰克？
Jack the Ripper?
太荒唐了，他是好几百年前的人了
Well, that's ridiculous. He lived hundreds of years ago.
一个人不可能存活好几个世纪的
A man couldn't survive all these centuries.
就在她死之前…
Just before she died...
…我妻子说
...my wife said,
“那是永生不死的
"It is a hunger
饥饿”
that never dies."
- 但所有人都会死 - 对，所有人都会死
- But all men die. - Yes, all men die.
开膛手杰克也是人，不可能现在还活着
And Jack the Ripper couldn't be alive if he were a man.
但我们所发现的事实都指向开膛手杰克
But everything we've uncovered points to Jack the Ripper,
这不可能啊，对吧？
which is an impossibility, isn't it?
还是说，有可能
Or is it?
人类及类人生物只构成了
Humans and humanoids make up only a small percentage
我们已知生命形式的很小一部分
of the life forms we know of.
有些存在物的生命周期极长
There are entities possessed of extremely long life spans,
几乎是永生的
virtually immortal.
我们知道，某人或…
We know that someone or...
…某种东西杀死了三名女性
...something killed three women.
如果不可能是人类，那一定是别的东西
If it's impossible for it to be human, it has to be something else.
- 某种有动机去杀人的东西 - 但赛柏说它是以死亡为食的
- Something driven to kill. - But Sybo said that it feeds on death.
从科学角度严格来讲，我们都是以死亡为食的
In the strict scientific sense, doctor, we all feed on death.
包括素食者
Even vegetarians.
对，但不止如此，不止是死亡，还有恐惧
Yes, but it said more than that. Not just death, but fear.
还说它以恐惧为食
Said it also feeds on fear.
这样一来，凶手不是人类的可能性
Which would tend to support the proposition
就有了根据
that the murderer was not human.
以情绪为食，目前在银河系尚不为人所知
Deriving sustenance from emotion is not unknown in the galaxy,
恐惧是所有情绪中最为强烈且最倾向于暴力的
and fear is among the strongest and most violent of the emotions.
长官，我们扯得太远了
Surely, prefect, this has gone far enough.
有人谋杀了三名女性
Someone, some man, has killed three women.
主要嫌疑人就在我们手上
We have the prime suspect in our hands.
我们却要去找什么鬼魂吗？
Are we going to let him go and start chasing ghosts?
亨吉斯先生，不是什么鬼魂
No, Mr. Hengist. Not ghosts.
很可能凶手不是人类，但也不是鬼魂 史波克先生，检查一下可能性
Possibly not human, but not ghosts. Mr. Spock, check out the possibilities.
计算机，分析过去五分钟的日志记录
Computer, digest log recordings for past five solar minutes.
相关假设，与已注册生命形式进行对比
Correlate hypotheses. Compare with life forms registered.
问题：我们所讨论的此类存在物
Question: Could such an entity, within discussed limits,
可能存在于银河系中吗？
exist in this galaxy?
船底座V的德瑞拉星
The Drella of Alpha Carinae V
以爱的情绪为营养
derives nourishment from the emotion of love.
这种生物确有先例存在
There is sufficient precedent for existence of creature,
种类不详
nature unknown,
可以依靠恐惧存活
which could exist on emotion of fear.
计算机，推测一下最具可能性的存在物
Computer, extrapolate most likely composition of such entity.
处理中，为满足上述要求
Working. To meet with specified requirements,
此类实体并非以传统方式存在
entity would exist without form in conventional sense.
很有可能以能量聚集的方式存在
Most probable, mass of energy.
一种高度凝聚的电磁场
A highly cohesive electromagnetic field.
计算机…
Computer...
…上述存在物…
...could the described entity...
…是否可能有物质形态？
...assume physical form?
确认，先例如下：
Affirmative. Precedent:
默利图斯，气态生物，来自阿尔法梅爵斯I星
Mellitus, cloud creature of Alpha Majoris I.
- 都是鬼话，什么神神鬼鬼的 - 不
- Fairy tales. Ghosts and goblins. - No.
我亲眼见过默利图斯
I've seen the Mellitus myself.
是它的自然状态，就是气体的
In its natural state, it's gaseous.
它休息的时候，是固体的
When it's at rest, it's solid.
史波克先生，我们假设这种生物的存在
Mr. Spock, let's assume the existence of this creature.
容我指出，开膛手杰克杀人时随心所欲
I point out that Jack the Ripper slew at will
在旧地球最繁华的都市行凶，从未被发现
in the heart of the most populous city of old Earth, and was never identified.
看起来不太可能，对吧？
Doesn't seem likely, does it?
我建议使用催眠仪扫描
I suggest the possibility of a hypnotic screen,
能屏蔽所有杂念，让受害者能看到凶手的形象
which blinds all but the victim to the presence of the killer.
- 这有可能吗？ - 很有可能
- Is that possible? - Extremely possible.
自然界中存在许多这样的例子
There are many such examples that exist in nature.
这简直就是幻想
Well, this is fantasy.
我们都知道凶手当时就和我们坐在一起
We all know the murderer is sitting right here with us,
但你却试图混淆视听，我觉得你是…
but you're trying to cloud the issue. I've got a mind to...
我很满意这次调查过程，非常有理有据
I am satisfied the course of this investigation is valid enough.
请坐下，亨吉斯先生
Please be seated, Mr. Hengist.
好了，史波克先生，我们现在有什么线索？
All right, Mr. Spock. What do we have?
一种没有形体的生物
A creature without form
依靠恐怖和惧怕存活
that feeds on horror and fear,
杀人时需要变成实体
that must assume a physical shape to kill.
另外，我推测，它的猎物是女性
And, I suspect, preys on women,
因为女性更容易被吓到
because women are more easily and more deeply terrified,
会比男性产生更多的恐惧情绪
generating more sheer horror than the male of the species.
计算机，犯罪学资料
Computer, criminological files.
开膛手杰克之后的未破解女性连环谋杀案件
Cases of unsolved mass murders of women since Jack the Ripper.
处理中，1932年，地球，中国，上海
Working. 1932, Shanghai, China, Earth.
七名女性被用刀刺死
Seven women knifed to death.
1974年，地球，旧苏联，基辅
1974, Kiev, USSR, Earth.
五名女性被用刀刺死
Five women knifed to death.
2105年，火星殖民地
2105, the Martian Colonies.
八名女性被用刀刺死
Eight women knifed to death.
2156年，海丽波利斯，阿尔法波江星座II
2156, Heliopolis, Alpha Eridani II.
十名女性被用刀刺死
Ten women knifed to death.
还有更多这样的例子
There are additional examples.
舰长，这些地方刚好在埃及列斯和地球之间
Captain, those places are aligned directly between Argelius and Earth.
是
Yes.
当人类迁移到银河系时
When man moved out into the galaxy,
那东西也一定跟来了
that thing must have moved with him.
计算机
Computer.
识别以下名称，科斯拉和博拉迪斯
Identify the proper names Kesla and Beratis.
处理中，科斯拉:
Working. Kesla:
人们给天津四II星球上
Name given to unidentified mass murderer of women
未归案女性连环杀手起的名字
on planet Deneb II.
博拉迪斯：
Beratis:
人们给参宿七4星球上
Name given to unidentified mass murderer of women
未归案女性连环杀手起的名字
on planet Rigel IV.
其他信息：
Additional data:
参宿七4号星的杀人凶手去年出现在某星系
Murders on Rigel IV occurred one solar year ago.
你来自参宿七-4
You come from Rigel IV.
很多人都是啊，这又不犯罪
Well, many people do. It's not a crime.
确实，但我们正在调查的就是罪案
No, but what we're investigating is.
请上座吧，亨吉斯先生
Would you mind taking the stand, Mr. Hengist?
- 我拒绝 - 亨吉斯先生
- I will not. - Mr. Hengist.
长官，这太过分了，我拒绝
Prefect, this has gone far enough. I will not take the stand.
我理解你的处境，先生
I can appreciate your position, sir.
你掌管当地的民事纠纷
You are in charge of civil disturbances locally.
如果你是我们要找的实体
If you are the entity for which we search,
还有什么比这个职位更能让你毫无顾忌的杀人呢
what better position from which to kill with impunity.
你离开嘉利斯家以后
And just after you left Jaris' house,
我们就发现行凶的刀子不见了
we discovered the murder knife was missing.
你也从未对特雷西上尉的死作出解释
And you were unaccounted for when Lieutenant Tracy was murdered.
一个靠害怕和恐惧存活的实体
An entity which feeds on fear and terror
能在埃及列斯找到完美的狩猎场所
would find a perfect hunting ground on Argelius,
这里没有暴力
a planet without violence,
居民们都热爱和平
where the inhabitants are as peaceful as sheep.
凶手在这里一定会像饥饿的孤狼一样
The entity would be as a hungry wolf in that fold.
各位，我了解法律
Gentlemen, I know something of the law.
你们现在纯属猜测
You're engaging in sheer speculation.
可能吧
Perhaps.
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock...
…杀人凶器
...the murder weapon.
计算机，证物A分析报告
Computer, report on analysis of exhibit A.
处理中，证物A外部形象
Working. Exhibit A on visual.
刀刃组成：砵锐锭
Composition of blade: Boridium.
刀柄组成：慕瑞矿
Composition of handle: Murinite.
刀柄上的雕刻图案属于某种民间艺术形式
Details of carving on handle conform to folk-art forms
可得出其来源地
indicating place of origin.
具体来源地
Specify point of origin.
此物品由参宿七4星，阿格斯河的山地人制造
Artefact produced by hill people of Argus River region, planet Rigel IV.
好了，亨吉斯先生
Now, then, Mr. Hengist.
- 他死了，吉姆 - 怎么可能呢
- He's dead, Jim. - But that's impossible.
瑞吉克，瑞吉克，瑞吉克！
Redjac. Redjac. Redjac!
计算机没有反应了
The computer will not respond to these controls.
它被这东西控制了
The entity is unquestionably controlling it.
计算机又控制着整个星舰
And the computer controls the ship.
瑞吉克，瑞吉克，瑞吉克，瑞吉克！
Redjac. Redjac. Redjac. Redjac!
史考特，帮帮我
Scotty, give me a hand.
没用的，舰长，旁路电路已经锁定了
No use, captain. The bypass circuits are blocked.
切断音频，史波克
Audio cut-off, Spock.
舰长
Captain.
- 怎么回事，舰长？ - 这是什么意思？
- What's happening, captain? - What does it mean?
意思是，这东西已经控制了整个星舰
It means that thing can control the entire operation of the ship,
包括生命维持系统
including the life-support systems.
你是说它可以杀了我们所有人？
You mean it could kill us all?
没错，它会尝试，但没那么快
Indeed, it will try, but not immediately.
我们知道这东西靠恐惧存活
We know it feeds on fear and terror.
这艘舰上有近440人
There are nearly 440 humans aboard this ship.
在它杀人之前肯定会想办法制造恐惧的
Surely it will try to breed fear and terror before it kills.
全体都有，我是舰长，请各位坚守岗位，保持冷静
All hands, this is the captain. Stay at your posts. Remain calm.
完毕
Captain out.
老骨头，你那儿有什么镇定剂吗？
Bones, what's the sedative situation?
我有能让活火山冷静下来的猛药
I've got some stuff that would tranquilize an active volcano.
很好，赶快分发吧
Good. Start distribution immediately.
我们拖的越久
The longer we can hold back that fear,
把那东西赶出计算机的可能性就越大
the more time we'll have to get that thing out of the computer.
长官，你们在这里更安全些，史波克，跟我来
Prefect, you'll all be safer here. Spock, come with me.
我记得你给计算机里面植入了强制扫描组件？
Don't you have a compulsory scan unit built into the computer banks?
是，但是现在被它控制了…
Yes, we do, but with the entity in control...
还有不能解决的
Aren't there certain mathematical problems
- 数学问题吗？ - 没错
- which simply cannot be solved? - Indeed.
如果我们能让计算机的 注意力集中在一个问题…
If we could focus the attention of the computer on one of them...
应该就行了
That ought to do it.
史波克
Spock.
很明显，我们这位新朋友学的很快
Apparently, our friend's learned very quickly.
学的太快了，舰桥
Too quickly. Bridge.
- 自由下落 - 失控了，手动控制吧
- Free fall. - Out of control. Put it on manual.
舰桥
Bridge.
这本来就是下一项了，维生系统故障了
That was due to be next. Life-support malfunction.
- 我们时间不多了，舰长 - 你自己说过的，史波克
- We don't have much time, captain. - You said it yourself, Spock.
它要的是恐惧，而不只是死亡
It wants terror. Not just death.
舰长，维生系统被干扰了
Captain, the life-support-system override jammed.
- 很好，就位吧，苏鲁先生 - 是，舰长
- All right, man your station, Mr. Sulu. - Aye, sir.
寇克舰长，舰长，你这是在浪费时间
Captain Kirk. Captain, you are wasting your time.
把那玩意儿关了
Cut that thing off.
你还有你的全体船员，都将死无葬身之地
You and all aboard your ship are about to die!
想办法关了它
Try and cut that thing off.
我还是头一次听到系统故障威胁我们
This is the first time I heard a malfunction threaten us.
就位，苏鲁先生
Man your post, Mr. Sulu.
准备好手动控制，可能会用得着
Prepare your manual overrides. You may need them.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
史波克
Spock.
已经恢复了普通环境水平，舰长
Normal environmental levels have been restored, captain,
但是持续不了多久，最多几个小时
but it will not last long. A few hours at best.
应该够了，我们行动吧
That should be enough time. Let's get at it.
- 怎么回事，舰长？ - 别担心，苏鲁先生
- What's going on, captain? - Never mind, Mr. Sulu.
- 镇定剂？ - 是，舰长
- Tranquilizer? - Yes, sir.
- 大家都要服，包括你自己 - 是，舰长
- Everyone, including yourself. - Yes, sir.
你没法阻止我的，舰长，没用的
You cannot stop me now, captain. It will do you no good.
我控制着所有回路，你没法屏蔽我的声音
I control all circuits. You cannot silence me.
也没法触碰到我
You cannot reach me.
你的手动控制根本奈何不了我
Your manual overrides are extremely limited in life.
史波克？
Spock?
还是处理中，舰长，我还需要一点时间
Proceeding, captain, but I will need some time.
明白了
Yes, I know.
很快，我就会恢复所有控制权
Soon, all control will be restored to me.
你无能为力，阻止不了我的
There is nothing you can do to prevent it.
如果你毁了这艘星舰，也就毁了你自己
If you destroy this ship, you destroy yourself.
我是没有终结的
I am without ending.
自时间之始我就存在，我将超越一切终点
I have existed from the dawn of time, and I shall live beyond its end.
我将饱餐一顿，这一次，不再需要用刀杀人
I shall feed, and this time I do not need a knife.
你们都将在恐惧中惨死
You will all die horribly
都将痛苦不堪
in searing pain.
它在试图制造恐惧，舰长
It is attempting to generate terror, captain.
我会切断你们的氧气，让你们窒息而死
I may cut off your oxygen and suffocate you.
舰长
Captain.
这家伙说话不怎么讨人喜欢啊
Whoever he is, he sure talks gloomy.
坚守战斗岗位，苏鲁
Man your post, Sulu.
要是其他系统也有故障就换成手动
If any of the other systems go out, switch to manual override.
还有，最重要的是，不要害怕
And above all, don't be afraid.
有了这东西，超新星撞来我也不怕
With an arm full of this stuff, I wouldn't be afraid of a supernova.
- 准备 - 实施
- Ready. - Implement.
计算机，下面是一级强制指令
Computer, this is a Class A compulsory directive.
计算至π的最后一位数
Compute to the last digit the value of pi.
不！不！
No, no! No!
据我们所知，π值是无穷尽
As we know, the value of pi is a transcendental figure
且无法计算的
without resolution.
计算机会优先解决这个问题
The computer banks will work on this problem
暂时搁置其他，直到我们命令它停下来
to the exclusion of all else, until we order it to stop.
没错，够它忙一会儿的了
Yes, that should keep that thing busy for a while.
埃及列斯人肯定会首先慌乱起来 我们去简报室看看情况
The Argelians will be the first to panic. Let's get back to the Briefing Room.
我在想，这个我们不该害怕的人是谁
I wonder who it is we're not supposed to be afraid of.
怎么样，舰长？
Well, sir?
我很怀疑计算机
I doubt very much whether the computers
能被两方势力控制多久
will be inhabited by more than a group of figures for a while.
会有阻力，但是强制指令目前占上风
There is resistance, captain, but the directive is succeeding.
数据库一个接一个都出现故障了
Bank after bank is turning to the problem.
你把它从计算机里赶出去，它会另觅他处的
If you drive it from the computers, it'll go somewhere else.
怎么样了？
How are you doing?
快完了，还剩嘉利斯和我
I'm almost finished. Just Jaris and me.
完成计算机控制了，舰长，那东西跑了
Complete computer control, captain. The entity has fled.
但是去哪里了呢？
Yes, but where to?
老骨头，如果那东西
Bones, what would happen if that thing
控制了一个已经注射了镇定剂的人，会怎样？
entered a tranquilized body?
可能会拿起针织毛衣 不会有什么过分暴力的行为
It might take up knitting, nothing more violent than that.
你说除了你和嘉利斯所有人都注射了？
And you say everyone's had a shot but you and Jaris?
还除了你和史波克先生，舰长
And you and Mr. Spock, captain.
我去瞧瞧史波克怎样了
Well, I'm willing to take a chance on Mr. Spock.
- 给自己最好也注射吧，医生 - 不了，我还是保持清醒吧
- Better give yourself a shot, doctor. - No, I think I want to stay clear.
照我说的做
Do as I say.
把手臂伸出来，嘉利斯先生
Extend your arm, Mr. Jaris.
不！杀光所有人，去死吧！受苦去吧！
No! Kill you all. Die! Make you suffer!
全部后退，我会杀了她的，后退
Everybody, keep back. I'll kill her. I'll kill her. Keep back.
小心，你会伤到别人的
Be careful. You're going to hurt somebody with that thing.
你们都将煎熬，你们…
You'll suffer, you...
杀光所有
Kill all.
带他去传送室，快
Let's get him to the Transporter Room, quick.
去死吧，全都去死吧
Die, die, die, everybody.
去死
Die.
杀…杀光所有
Kill, kill, kill you all.
外太空，全功率，最宽角离散，保持状态
Deep space, full power. Widest angle of dispersion. Maintain.
别太兴奋了，舰长，我这就来
Don't get excited, captain. I'll do it.
你来吧，史波克
You do it, Spock.
所有人，去死
Everybody, die.
你干嘛推我，史波克先生 跟你说了我会做的嘛
You didn't have to shove me, Mr. Spock. I'd have gotten round to it.
嘉利斯没事了
Well, Jaris is all right.
你把那东西怎么了，送回原来的星球了？
What did you do with that thing, send it back to the planet?
不是，我们把它传送到外太空了
No, we beamed it out into open space, Scotty,
- 宽广无垠的外太空 - 那东西死不了
- widest possible dispersion. - The thing can't die.
很可能它的意识还会存在一段时间，医生
Possibly, doctor. It's consciousness may continue for some time,
分散为无数小能量团
consisting of billions of separate bits of energy,
永远漂浮在太空里，但没有力量
floating forever in space, powerless.
但是它最终会死的
But it will die, finally.
整件事情让你很开心啊
You seem very happy about the whole thing.
为什么不呢？有那么一会儿
And why not? For a while there,
我都不知道自己究竟是有罪的还是无辜的
I didn't know whether I was innocent or guilty.
老骨头，镇定剂还要多久才失效？
Bones, how long will it take for this tranquilizer to wear off?
不知道，五六个小时吧，我给的剂量挺大的
Oh, I don't know, five or six hours. I gave them all a pretty big shot, Jim.
看得出来
Yes, I can see that.
史波克先生，接下来的五六个小时
Mr. Spock, for the next five or six hours
我们将面对整个太空中最快乐的船员们
we're gonna have the happiest crew in space.
自然，也没什么工作要做
Of course, we won't get much work done.
舰长，既然你是来埃及列斯休整的
Captain, since you came to Argelius to rest,
何不好好抓住这个机会呢
I suggest you take advantage of the opportunity.
这主意不错，史波克先生
That's a splendid idea, Mr. Spock.
我知道有一家咖啡店，那里的姑娘都特别…
I know a café where the women are so...
- 我知道那地方，吉姆 - 去看看吧
- I know the place, Jim. - Let's go see.
先生，就你现在这样，还是别出洋相了吧
You gentlemen, in your condition? Don't be ridiculous.
史波克先生，那家咖啡店的姑娘们都…
Mr. Spock, this café has women that are so...
还是算了
No, I guess not.
自己去？
Alone?
各位请吧
Gentlemen.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/